Nitish Chopra

Software Developer

nitishchopranc.nc@gmail.com

+91-9780118944

linkedin.com/in/nchopra96

Having 2.5+ years of experience as a Software Developer with experience in multifaceted roles requiring project management, business development, and solutions architecture. Skilled in the areas of Big Data analytics, Spark and MySQL. Having interest in designing large scale distributed systems.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Systems Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

06/2019 - Present Achievements/Tasks Chennai, India

- Developed a near real time security orchestration pipeline that helps in detecting external malicious sources from firewall traffic in less than 1 min by using our own IP Reputation solution with streaming technology.
- Developed project features using OOPs (object-oriented concepts) and design pattern which adhered to proper guidelines and algorithmic techniques.
- Responsible for reducing manual steps by **90 percent** by developing an interactive dashboard which displays **security indicators** based on the given data using python.
- **User Behavior Analytics** using layered data analysis approach through ingestion, analytics and created a dashboard displaying the key risk Indicators and alarming mechanisms.
- Developed a **Spark streaming pipeline** to ingest Firewall data and display security metrics in a real time dashboard using Plotly Dash.
- Experienced with Software Development frameworks such as **Scrum**, **Agile** and responsible for handling daily scrum in my team.
- Developed a dashboard to identify log source and display their corresponding indicators.
- Developed a framework to **detect log anomalies** by **Spark** batch processing of various log data ingested from different
- Actively participated in sprint review demos of the project and deliverables helped in revenue generation for organization.

Intern

Tata Consultancy Services

01/2019 - 04/2019

Chennai,India

- Achievements/Tasks
- Write, analyze, review, and rewrite programs, using workflow chart and diagram related to **security tools**.
- Applied knowledge of computer capabilities, subject matter, and symbolic logic in understanding different security related attacks and vulnerabilities.
- Researched about various security related tools corresponding to various security related risks.

EDUCATION

O B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering Guru Nanak Dev University

08/2015 - 04/2019 9.1 CGPA

SKILLS

Python	• • • • •
Data Structures and Algorithms	
Object Oriented Concepts	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
Hadoop	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
Spark	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
MySQL	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
Database Management System	\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ
Google Cloud Platform	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ
Linux	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ
Kafka	\bullet \bullet \circ \circ

CODING PROFILES/ ACHIEVEMENTS

Achieved 2.5 stars on Leetcode for solving problems and solved 300+ problems https://leetcode.com/NChopra/

Achieved 5 star Golden Badge in HackerRank for SQL and Problem Solving.

https://www.hackerrank.com/nitishchopra34

Solved 100+ problems on Geeks For Geeks https://auth.geeksforgeeks.org/user/nitishchoprancnc/profile

Represented India in Global Finals of Huawei ICT Skill Competition held at Shenzhen, China

I secured 3rd rank in the finals of Huawei ICT Skill Competition 2017-18 thus I got the chance to represent India at the Global Finals

Innovation pride award

Awarded with Innovation Pride award for outstanding contribution to the organisation.

CERTIFICATIONS

Google Cloud certified Professional Data Engineer (06/2021 - 06/2023)

Certification ID: fkzeRS

Huawei Certified Network Associate - Routing and Switching (11/2019 - 11/2021)

Certificate no. - 010100101393807258691441